<xliff xmlns="urn:oasis:names:tc:xliff:document:2.0" version="2.0" srcLang="es" trgLang="en">
 <file id="b71f4e39-bf5d-4466-8a75-81d5fc25278c" original="LOWFUZZIES_25. GA30044_EC Clarification request_28Oct2016 - ESP.pdf">
  <skeleton href="" />
  <unit id="f4444fcc-4473-4b52-b588-437ad6cb29e0">
   <segment>
    <source>DICTAMEN DEL COMITÉ AUTONÓMICO DE ÉTICA DE LA INVESTIGACIÓN DE GALICIA</source>
    <target>OPINION OF THE AUTONOMOUS RESEARCH ETHICS COMMITTEE OF GALICIA</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="3142ee07-07d7-4bc1-b202-279103b79ff8">
   <segment>
    <source>Paula M.</source>
    <target>Paula M.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="e34b6d59-f741-416a-bceb-719a0fd1cbc1">
   <segment>
    <source>López Vázquez, Secretaria del Comité Autonómico de Ética de la Investigación de Galicia,</source>
    <target>López Vázquez, Secretary of the Autonomous Research Ethics Committee of Galicia,</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="15d0141e-526c-40ee-a380-c80d90a5e1bd">
   <segment>
    <source>CERTIFICA:</source>
    <target>HEREBY CERTIFIES:</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="ffda6cd8-730e-41cd-b948-afca0b3af832">
   <segment>
    <source>Que este Comité evaluó en la reunión celebrada el día 27/10/16 la propuesta del ensayo clínico:</source>
    <target>That, at the meeting held on 10/27/16, this Committee evaluated the proposal for the clinical trial:</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="19c734f1-ecfa-4514-85c5-308c32eb26a0">
   <segment>
    <source>Nº EudraCT: 2016-001039-11</source>
    <target>EudraCT No.: 2016-001039-11</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="54bcefa0-c368-42de-a2db-1f2f399b1c2c">
   <segment>
    <source>Título: Estudio en fase II, aleatorizado, doble ciego y controlado con placebo de la seguridad y la eficacia de GDC-0853 en pacientes con lupus eritematoso sistémico activo de moderado a grave</source>
    <target>Title: Phase II, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study of the safety and efficacy of GDC-0853 in patients with moderate to severe active systemic lupus erythematosus</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="cd5ac2ce-73ef-4850-adb0-b8388259239c">
   <segment>
    <source>Código del promotor: GA30044 Código de Registro: 2016/489 Promotor:Genentech, Inc.</source>
    <target>Sponsor Code: GA30044 Registration Code: 2016/489 Sponsor: Genentech, Inc.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="4016ead7-18c7-438a-b499-d7ad667fad59">
   <segment>
    <source>Versión/fecha del protocolo y Hoja de Información al Paciente: Versión 1 de 27 de junio de 2016; HIP y CI, Spanish Main Subject Informed consent Form Version 01ESP(es)01 dated 03Aug2016; HIP y CI para la obtención opcional de muestras biológicas para investigación, Spanish RBR ICF V1.0ESP (es)01dated 12Aug2016;</source>
    <target>Version/date of protocol and Patient Information Sheet: Version 1 of June 27, 2016; PIS and IC, Spanish Main Subject Informed Consent Form Version 01ESP(es)01 dated 03Aug2016; PIS and IC for optional collection of biological samples for research, Spanish RBR ICF V1.0ESP(es)01 dated 12Aug2016;</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="7f64a2a9-81c3-499c-a14f-2eb6ebd5ecc8">
   <segment>
    <source>Formulario de consentimiento informado y seguimiento de la pareja embarazada,</source>
    <target>Pregnant partner Informed Consent Form and follow-up,</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="ed405b88-0cba-4c0d-9791-70c3e9635ba0">
   <segment>
    <source>Spanish Pregnant Partner ICF V1.0ESP(es)01dated 05Aug2016</source>
    <target>Spanish Pregnant Partner ICF V1.0ESP(es)01dated 05Aug2016</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="cf3519d6-dd2c-45df-bbd7-d2e44e49faf8">
   <segment>
    <source>Que este Comité ha realizado la evaluación de la parte II de la solicitud de autorización del ensayo, de acuerdo con lo previsto en el Real Decreto 1090/2015 y en el art 7 del reglamento (UE) 536/2014 y ha decidido SOLICITAR LAS ACLARACIONES que se listan a continuación:</source>
    <target>That this Committee has carried out the evaluation of part II of the application for authorization of the trial, in accordance with the provisions of Royal Decree 1090/2015 and Article 7 of Regulation (EU) 536/2014 and has decided to REQUEST THE CLARIFICATIONS listed below:</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="b72ce65e-8baf-48d1-9d8e-e80ea74c9020">
   <segment>
    <source>Remitir de nuevo el documento de idoneidad de las instalaciones del centro de Murcia (incluyendo nombre y cargo de la persona que lo firma).</source>
    <target>Resubmit the document on the suitability of the facilities at the Murcia site (including name and position of the person signing it).</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="da5b56e2-449e-4299-9188-7fb87a3deb7e">
   <segment>
    <source>Materiales de reclutamiento: dado el tamaño muestral previsto y el numero de pacientes por centro (1) no consideramos preciso el uso de metodos destinados a la población general (en concreto el Newspaper Advertisement y los Postings).</source>
    <target>Recruitment materials: given the expected sample size and the number of patients per site (1) we do not consider it necessary to use methods intended for the general population (namely the Newspaper Advertisement and the Postings).</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="821b343a-1b26-401f-8cae-e9b7ae13833d">
   <segment>
    <source>El resto de documentos dirigidos a población con LES, los dejamos a criterio de uso de cada centro en base a sus normas de regulamiento interno.</source>
    <target>As for the rest of the documents addressed to population with SLE, we leave them to the criteria of use of each site based on its internal standards.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="4bb11b89-e6cc-4151-9d3a-5902e73ec9bd">
   <segment>
    <source>Documentos de consentimiento</source>
    <target>Consent Documents</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="ff3dfd53-eeac-40db-9c7f-8e9753fb1fab">
   <segment>
    <source>La hoja de información del estudio principal es excesivamente larga, les recomendamos que hagan un ejercicio de síntesis para facilitar la lectura a los participantes (no debería exceder las 15 hojas).</source>
    <target>The Main study information sheet is excessively long. We recommend that you shorten it, in order to facilitate reading for the participants (it should not exceed 15 pages).</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="eba41e1b-51ce-45be-87d8-3944ab91427b">
   <segment>
    <source>A este respecto, hay apartados que podrían resumirse como las menciones a analíticas a realizar,  riesgos del ECG o de radiografías.</source>
    <target>In this respect, there are sections that could be summarized, such as the descriptions of analyses to be performed, ECG or X-ray risks.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="56643c09-581b-43e2-a98a-704abd7e3d87">
   <segment>
    <source>En el apartado de responsabilidad ante daños no procede la descripción de las coberturas y no coberturas, sino que se debe mencionar únicamente que el promotor ha contratado una póliza de seguro de acuerdo a lo establecido en el</source>
    <target>In the section on liability for damage, the description of coverage and non-coverage is not relevant; it need only be stated that the sponsor has taken out an insurance policy in accordance with the stipulations of</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="ddebf9f7-6d2f-40de-b9d5-6b1a05c8823c">
   <segment>
    <source>R.D 1090/2015 así como la compañía, y que ante la sospecha de haber  sufrido alguna lesión debe informar a su médico.</source>
    <target>R.D 1090/2015, giving the name of the company, and that anyone who suspects they have suffered any harm should inform their doctor.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="c0ccbf03-caf1-4a24-aba6-772e548575f1">
   <segment>
    <source>Consideramos que también podría reducirse la descripción de los  efectos del medicamento en investigación en animales.</source>
    <target>We believe that the description of the effects of the investigational drug on animals could also be shortened.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="5a616c59-b7cf-41a2-9219-afdd307e7467">
   <segment>
    <source>Hacer mención completa al título de las normas para que el participante puede identificarlas de manera más sencilla y consultarlas si lo desea (nos referimos en particular a las menciones a RD 1090/2015 y BPC/CPMP/ICH que se ofrece en la pág.</source>
    <target>Mention the titles of the regulations in full so that the participant can identify them more easily and consult them if desired (in particular, the references to RD 1090/2015 and GPC/CPMP/ICH on page</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="1768ca03-405a-435a-bcdd-75443e220f23">
   <segment>
    <source>Añadir que el investigador recibirá una compensación económica por participar.</source>
    <target>Add that the investigator will receive financial compensation for participating.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="b577e644-bafd-46cc-b401-33a00ff27b9f">
   <segment>
    <source>Con respecto a la mención que repiten en varios apartados “autoriza al centro del estudio a usar o divulgar (compartir) su información médica que permita identificarle para los fines de este ensayo clínico”, consideramos que debiera ser retirada y dejar suficientemente claro, que la información clínica que salga del centro sanitario será solo identificada por un código y sin datos de carácter personal que puedan identificarle de manera directa.</source>
    <target>Regarding the repeated statement in several paragraphs, "authorize the study site to use or disclose (share) your medical information that will allow us to identify you for the purposes of this clinical trial", we consider that it should be withdrawn and that it should be made sufficiently clear that clinical information that leaves the health site will only be identified by a code and without any personal data by which patients could be identified directly.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="5bb7c962-3316-44dc-a70f-118531d67c98">
   <segment>
    <source>Tal como está descrito puede confundir al participante.</source>
    <target>The way in which it is currently described could confuse the participant.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="175d633a-52da-4749-baa5-effaee4adef5">
   <segment>
    <source>En general les recomendamos que dentro del ejercicio de síntesis intenten resumir el antepenúltimo y penúltimo apartados en uno (dado que se repite información sobre el manejo de datos).</source>
    <target>In general, we recommend that, as part of the shortening process, you try to summarize the antepenultimate and penultimate sections into one (since the data handling information is repeated).</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="a227737d-f8dc-4d22-9c0e-de5385fca7d6">
   <segment>
    <source>Falta la opción de consentimiento oral  ante testigo para pacientes capaces pero con alguna discapacidad que le impida leer/escribir.</source>
    <target>There is no option of oral consent in the presence of a witness for capable patients with disabilities that prevent them from reading/writing.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="4bed5076-3f37-40c8-a060-a57a5ec205ca">
   <segment>
    <source>Ante la posibilidad de teratogenia debe asegurarse la asistencia médica en cualquier caso con una fórmula como "se pondrán a su disposición la atención médica y los medios necesarios en consonancia con la decisión que Vd.</source>
    <target>In view of the possibility of teratogenesis, medical assistance should be assured in any case with a phrase such as "medical care and the necessary resources will be provided in accordance with the decision you make</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="3d2db278-45ff-4855-b334-9f9028808fcd">
   <segment>
    <source>adopte sobre su embarazo".</source>
    <target>about your pregnancy".</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="13886472-87d2-4f07-982c-2bb30f93fe30">
   <segment>
    <source>Advertir de las potenciales consecuencias que participar en un ensayo clínico pueden tener sobre las condiciones de seguros privados (como seguros de vida) que puedan tener contratados los participantes.</source>
    <target>Warn about the potential consequences that participating in a clinical trial may have on the conditions of private insurance policies (such as life insurance) that participants may have taken out.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="8ebb940b-6f7d-4d6c-af82-87e5c312ce5f">
   <segment>
    <source>No se acepta la mención “no se compartirán ni con usted ni con su médico ...”.</source>
    <target>The mention of "will not be shared with you or your doctor ..." is not acceptable.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="8a873553-9c9d-4730-be38-0378cbfb35df">
   <segment>
    <source>A priori, se debe dar opción mientras las muestras estén codificadas a conocer los análisis y resultados de éstos que se hagan con las mismas, aun con la advertencia de que éstos resultados probablemente no tengan implicaciones clínicas individuales sino sólo interés científico.</source>
    <target>A priori, as long as the samples are coded, the option should be given to find out about the analyzes conducted using the samples and the results produced, with the warning that these results probably do not have individual clinical implications but are only of scientific interest.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="9a101cc5-3668-4b9c-a58f-3a08c218fedd">
   <segment>
    <source>Esto mismo es de aplicación para los usos futuros que se solicitan en documento aparte.</source>
    <target>The same is applicable for the future uses that are requested in a separate document.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="738d9295-6671-4641-9689-2d4eeccd3034">
   <segment>
    <source>Documentos muestras usos futuros / banco:  A este respecto y dado que los usos que se plantean son indefinidos y no centrados en una línea de investigación, la conservación de muestras para una vez rematado el plazo de conservación dentro de los procedimientos del ensayo, sólo procedería si se comprometen o bien a anonimizarlas o bien a almacenarlas en un Biobanco que cumpla los requisitos establecidos en Ley 14/2007, RD 1716/2011 (normas del país donde se da el acto de donación de la muestra) y a la Recomendación del Comité de Ministros a los estados miembros sobre investigación en muestras biológicas de origen humano REC (2016)6.</source>
    <target>Documents on the future uses/banking of samples: In this respect and given that the uses are unlimited and not centered on one line of research, the storage of samples - once the storage period stipulated as part of the trial procedures has ended - would only proceed if an undertaking is made either to anonymize them or to store them in a Biobank that meets the requirements established in Law 14/2007, RD 1716/2011 (standards of the country where the act of donating the sample is done) and the Recommendation of the Committee of Ministers to Member States on Research on Biological Materials of Human Origin REC (2016)6.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="8144680c-235a-4cfd-8acd-55866175717e">
   <segment>
    <source>Es importante que se indique que el banco de muestra está sujeto a una revisión externa e independiente de acuerdo a lo indicado en las mencionadas normas.</source>
    <target>It is important to indicate that the sample bank is subject to an external and independent review as indicated in the aforementioned regulations.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="84fcac5d-7b37-4db4-b8e5-508ab14fdbb6">
   <segment>
    <source>Que en dicha reunión se cumplieron los requisitos establecidos en la legislación vigente – Real Decreto 1090/2015 – para que la decisión del citado CEIm sea válida.</source>
    <target>That, at that meeting, the requirements set out in the applicable law - Royal Decree 1090/2015 - determining the validity of the decision of the aforementioned CEIm, were fulfilled.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="dc5752ba-5e3c-4b5a-9da6-d4179ca31f76">
   <segment>
    <source>Que el Comité  tanto en su composición como en sus procedimientos, cumple con las normas de BPC (CPMP/ICH/135/95) y con la legislación vigente que regula su funcionamiento,  y que la composición del mismo es la indicada en el anexo I, teniendo en cuenta que en el caso de que algún miembro participe en el ensayo o declare algún conflicto de interés, se ausentará durante la evaluación.</source>
    <target>That the Committee, both in its composition and procedures, complies with the GCP guidelines (CPMP/ICH/135/95) and with the applicable law governing its operation, and that its composition is indicated in Addendum I, taking into account that in the event that any member participates in the trial or declares any conflict of interest, they will be absent during the evaluation.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="76fdf413-fd2c-403e-8f56-2e3c95905449">
   <segment>
    <source>En Santiago de Compostela, a 28 de octubre de 2016</source>
    <target>In Santiago de Compostela, on October 28, 2016</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="4c0866bd-4676-4a26-b05d-cc72b9c3fcac">
   <segment>
    <source>Anexo I : Composición del Comité Autonómico de Ética de la Investigación de</source>
    <target>Addendum I: Composition of the Autonomous Research Ethics Committee of</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="a2a886fb-a7af-47c2-9df1-b045ba27393e">
   <segment>
    <source>Galicia (CAEIG)</source>
    <target>Galicia (CAEIG)</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="53df82a9-9362-4bbf-b1f3-b34ea93e2566">
   <segment>
    <source>Manuel Portela Romero.</source>
    <target>Manuel Portela Romero.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="3d3fa039-35ed-412e-987d-3abd17bfb201">
   <segment>
    <source>(Presidente).</source>
    <target>(Chairperson).</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="c5cf8cec-f9ab-45f9-9159-891b0fdb1618">
   <segment>
    <source>Médico Especialista en Medicina Familiar y Comunitaria.</source>
    <target>Medical Specialist in Family and Community Medicine.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="9f9546d9-6d72-402e-a0b1-6d42704f35c9">
   <segment>
    <source>Irene Zarra Ferro.</source>
    <target>Irene Zarra Ferro.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="9293e5ca-31db-49b5-a4c7-88c142f0c320">
   <segment>
    <source>(Vicepresidenta).</source>
    <target>(Vice-Chairperson).</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="3b9986f0-7dde-4e3e-9495-a59a1da8f741">
   <segment>
    <source>Farmacéutica de Atención Especializada.</source>
    <target>Specialist Care Pharmacist.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="a54f7e02-8013-4549-b4f7-935fc37307f9">
   <segment>
    <source>Paula Mª López Vázquez, (Secretaria).</source>
    <target>Paula María López Vázquez, (Secretary).</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="50b6aa0c-b806-4c01-9f2d-c6a02746acca">
   <segment>
    <source>Médico Especialista en Farmacología Clínica.</source>
    <target>Medical Specialist in Clinical Pharmacology.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="b854cbc0-e645-416c-94b6-471f20941944">
   <segment>
    <source>Juan Vázquez Lago  (Secretario Suplente).</source>
    <target>Juan Vázquez Lago (Alternate Secretary).</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="5b492dae-3e40-4c94-a9ae-36a7aaa9cafe">
   <segment>
    <source>Médico Especialista en Medicina Preventiva y Salud Pública.</source>
    <target>Medical Specialist in Preventive Medicine and Public Health.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="9fd52d2a-3b36-42ac-a1ec-81d5a5917e90">
   <segment>
    <source>Jesús Alberdi Sudupe.</source>
    <target>Jesús Alberdi Sudupe.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="ae8b4c29-0540-4f29-a7b5-6b75f72ccddd">
   <segment>
    <source>Médico especialista en Psiquiatría.</source>
    <target>Medical Specialist in Psychiatry.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="f0676b72-f239-4fe5-82ed-59f12de927e0">
   <segment>
    <source>Rosendo Bugarín González.</source>
    <target>Rosendo Bugarín González.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="b453072d-8284-4f23-a58a-ee525f5a1633">
   <segment>
    <source>Médico Especialista en Medicina Familiar y Comunitaria.</source>
    <target>Medical Specialist in Family and Community Medicine.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="8dc931c7-709f-4b7c-bbf8-1c9b1dbe6b85">
   <segment>
    <source>Juan Casariego Rosón.</source>
    <target>Juan Casariego Rosón.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="5360327b-d208-49cc-b0e8-5163b241411b">
   <segment>
    <source>Médico Especialista en Cardiología.</source>
    <target>Medical Specialist in Cardiology.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="2c5d9e5e-95cd-4554-a82c-ec0848348cfd">
   <segment>
    <source>Xoán X.</source>
    <target>Xoán X.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="d64ade27-0aef-4fd5-9fa4-a4b373967a9d">
   <segment>
    <source>Casas Rodríguez.</source>
    <target>Casas Rodríguez.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="89bda167-5510-4e15-a4ce-e89b89611c1b">
   <segment>
    <source>Médico Especialista en Medicina Familiar y Comunitaria.</source>
    <target>Medical Specialist in Family and Community Medicine.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="03c71f38-a8e6-4869-93bb-6c2dc1cdc440">
   <segment>
    <source>Juana Mª Cruz del Río.</source>
    <target>Juana María Cruz del Río.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="f1def8e6-e4ed-4c35-8eb6-1b2614146b82">
   <segment>
    <source>Trabajadora Social.</source>
    <target>Social Worker.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="2c6967fb-53f8-4fd1-aff4-8b78907b831d">
   <segment>
    <source>Juan Fernando Cueva Bañuelos.</source>
    <target>Juan Fernando Cueva Bañuelos.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="7c938509-18bb-43c4-86d6-80804b8fe08e">
   <segment>
    <source>Médico Especialista en Oncología Médica.</source>
    <target>Medical Specialist in Medical Oncology.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="ece0c01f-70a5-4822-96e1-f0f794120808">
   <segment>
    <source>José Álvaro Fernández Rial.</source>
    <target>José Álvaro Fernández Rial.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="b8e96088-9653-42c8-9fd7-40f348fb89c0">
   <segment>
    <source>Médico Especialista en Medicina Interna.</source>
    <target>Medical Specialist in Internal Medicine.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="27700c74-1029-4544-9024-b716252831c7">
   <segment>
    <source>José Luis Fernández Trisac.</source>
    <target>José Luis Fernández Trisac.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="d7b281f3-1f1b-4fc2-9f2a-1919b2a2c7f1">
   <segment>
    <source>Médico Especialista en Pediatría.</source>
    <target>Medical Specialist in Pediatrics.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="31ea3769-7c1f-4afe-9c07-a3176cfeb7a4">
   <segment>
    <source>Mª José Ferreira Díaz.</source>
    <target>María José Ferreira Díaz.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="0cc4989b-bacb-43fe-b328-b90e367a2371">
   <segment>
    <source>Diplomada Universitaria de Enfermería.</source>
    <target>Registered Nurse.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="c34ac951-a8b8-49b9-b232-5b2d533c8f01">
   <segment>
    <source>Pablo Nimo Ríos.</source>
    <target>Pablo Nimo Ríos.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="15344ed4-0c8c-435b-8c00-38fc7759b446">
   <segment>
    <source>Licenciado en Derecho.</source>
    <target>Graduate of Law.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="b69ae863-1007-4a21-bcda-cbdf8695cd3a">
   <segment>
    <source>Pilar Gayoso Diz.</source>
    <target>Pilar Gayoso Diz.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="bea63956-a27c-419f-8f59-f2b5b242832b">
   <segment>
    <source>Médico Especialista en Medicina Familiar y Comunitaria.</source>
    <target>Medical Specialist in Family and Community Medicine.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="ab6f443b-842d-4a65-ae1e-3874f42c5594">
   <segment>
    <source>Agustín Pía Morandeira.</source>
    <target>Agustín Pía Morandeira.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="a561e7e0-b59b-4aa9-9a09-b60d3ad822d6">
   <segment>
    <source>Farmacéutico de Atención Primaria</source>
    <target>Primary Care Pharmacist</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="31d89bee-2556-43a8-b24a-c1d7b2365534">
   <segment>
    <source>Salvador Pita Fernández.</source>
    <target>Salvador Pita Fernández.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="166dc890-1983-492d-9550-b91418bcb6d9">
   <segment>
    <source>Médico Especialista en Medicina Familiar y Comunitaria.</source>
    <target>Medical Specialist in Family and Community Medicine.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="d091f715-6808-438d-a9ca-7706c4dec9d3">
   <segment>
    <source>Carmen Rodríguez-Tenreiro Sánchez.</source>
    <target>Carmen Rodríguez-Tenreiro Sánchez.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="ba9da853-61ce-4b8e-a2ca-58dadaade9e5">
   <segment>
    <source>Licenciada en Farmacia.</source>
    <target>Graduate of Pharmacy.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="599d6257-768d-4af3-b442-a08f2cce7a7d">
   <segment>
    <source>Susana María Romero Yuste.</source>
    <target>Susana María Romero Yuste.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="2434a23f-9bed-4603-bcb9-b3606fd03feb">
   <segment>
    <source>Médico Especialista en Reumatología.</source>
    <target>Medical Specialist in Rheumatology.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="b3bdc72a-d22e-4af0-87d1-624cae463a47">
   <segment>
    <source>Mª Asunción Verdejo González.</source>
    <target>María Asunción Verdejo González.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="287279ee-045f-4442-a20b-33673a5407c6">
   <segment>
    <source>Médico Especialista en Farmacología Clínica.</source>
    <target>Medical Specialist in Clinical Pharmacology.</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="bc864dd8-02a9-4071-98a6-4aa18113be91">
   <segment>
    <source>CAEI de Galicia</source>
    <target>CAEI de Galicia</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="ea067a80-1292-4800-b0a6-798ace0779f7">
   <segment>
    <source>Edificio Administrativo San Lázaro</source>
    <target>Edificio Administrativo San Lázaro</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="e5677385-3248-4459-9b40-b3b5cc9e1261">
   <segment>
    <source>15703 SANTIAGO DE COMPOSTELA</source>
    <target>15703 SANTIAGO DE COMPOSTELA</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="6b55b8ed-0fd7-418f-aa82-01f66d07ebc0">
   <segment>
    <source>Teléfono: 881546425 ceic@sergas.es</source>
    <target>Phone: +34 881 546 425 ceic@sergas.es</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="aecbed34-857a-465d-aabd-dbc62695518f">
   <segment>
    <source>CAEI de Galicia</source>
    <target>CAEI de Galicia</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="9c85af50-3c59-4a4b-8e2d-d2815dc1eccb">
   <segment>
    <source>Edificio Administrativo San Lázaro</source>
    <target>Edificio Administrativo San Lázaro</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="d933a606-2cb2-462e-8b15-9b740b7fe65b">
   <segment>
    <source>15703 SANTIAGO DE COMPOSTELA</source>
    <target>15703 SANTIAGO DE COMPOSTELA</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="af3c27f8-15a7-44d5-bb5f-73508a77a399">
   <segment>
    <source>Teléfono: 881546425 ceic@sergas.es</source>
    <target>Phone: +34 881 546 425 ceic@sergas.es</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="697b62f5-5d5c-4a6a-907b-215cb6e1e0df">
   <segment>
    <source>CAEI de Galicia</source>
    <target>CAEI de Galicia</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="b5137593-2abe-42e5-9551-143a199dac16">
   <segment>
    <source>Edificio Administrativo San Lázaro</source>
    <target>Edificio Administrativo San Lázaro</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="64faa208-8136-470e-9e85-5e7f525a7656">
   <segment>
    <source>15703 SANTIAGO DE COMPOSTELA</source>
    <target>15703 SANTIAGO DE COMPOSTELA</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="dae3abf3-01ac-4795-85b6-ce9f805f866e">
   <segment>
    <source>Teléfono: 881546425 ceic@sergas.es</source>
    <target>Phone: +34 881 546 425 ceic@sergas.es</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="9e62ff0e-157a-414e-a9dc-855fa162072c">
   <segment>
    <source>XUNTFI DE GFILICIFI</source>
    <target>XUNTA DE GALICIA</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="7d5cc152-a520-4c4e-9d85-476d9ca82309">
   <segment>
    <source>CONSELLERiA DE SANIDADE</source>
    <target>MINISTRY OF HEALTH</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
  <unit id="e24c89ef-9490-4047-bf27-e362e5736270">
   <segment>
    <source>Secretaria Xeral Tecnica</source>
    <target>General Technical Secretary</target>
   </segment>
  </unit>
 </file>
 </xliff>
